{
    "id": "aed4ecb7549a4d8e8b54638b08aa6aff",
    "title": "Rather, Would Rather, Rather Than Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "e37e930396d64d94b63a64d7c4ba871e",
            "title": "Rather, Would Rather",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "He is ......................................",
                    "description": "Rather usually goes before articles. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "rather fool",
                        "a rather fool",
                        "rather a fool"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "That was .................................",
                    "description": "Rather can modify nouns. It usually goes before articles if there is no adjective. If there is an adjective it can go before or after articles. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "rather a good idea",
                        "a rather good idea",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "We ........................ hoping he would leave soon.",
                    "description": "Rather is an adverb. It goes after the auxiliary verb and before the main verb. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "rather were",
                        "were rather",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I would prefer to come on Tuesday .................... on Thursday.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "rather",
                        "would rather",
                        "rather than"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I decided to phone rather than ..................",
                    "description": "When the main clause has a to-infinitive, rather than is usually followed by an infinitive without to. An -ing form is also possible. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "write",
                        "writing",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "Would you rather ..................... here or go home.",
                    "description": "Would rather is followed by an infinitive without to. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "stay",
                        "to stay",
                        "staying"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I would rather ....................... something to eat.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "have",
                        "to have",
                        "having"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I would rather you ...................... me alone.",
                    "description": "After would rather, we use a past tense with present or future meaning. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "leave",
                        "left",
                        "leaving",
                        "had left"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "'Should I turn the heating on?' 'I would rather you .....................",
                    "description": "After would rather, we use a past tense with present or future meaning. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "not",
                        "didn't",
                        "hadn't"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "It is important to find new markets rather than .................... new people.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "hire",
                        "hiring",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "Rather than ........................ the last of my cash for a meal, I chose to stay hungry.",
                    "description": "Spend and spending are both possible here. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "spending",
                        "spend",
                        "to spend"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I would rather you ........................... that. You upset her.",
                    "description": "A past perfect tense is used after rather than to talk about past actions. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "didn't say",
                        "hadn't said",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}